<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>

	<Language_en_US>
		<!-- Czechia -->
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DAWN_OF_MAN_CZECHIA_TEXT">			
				<Text>Blessings upon you, Vladislav II, wise King of Bohemia and Hungary! Your reign ushered in a golden era of peace and cultural prosperity for the Czech lands. Under your rule, the magnificent Vladislav Hall of Prague Castle was constructed, standing as a testament to your patronage of Gothic architecture and the arts. Your diplomatic skill in balancing the interests of nobles and burghers helped maintain stability in your realm during turbulent times. Though remembered as a peaceful and consensus-seeking monarch, your legacy endures in the grand buildings and institutions that flourished during your reign.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Great King, your people call for your leadership once more. Can you guide them to glory through wisdom and diplomacy? Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?
				</Text>
			</Row>
			
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CZECHIA_MINT">				
				<Text>Thaler Mint</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_CZECHIA_MINT_TEXT">			
				<Text>The Thaler was a silver coin first minted in Jáchymov (then known as Joachimsthal) in the Kingdom of Bohemia in 1520. These coins gained immediate popularity throughout Europe due to their consistent weight and purity, setting a standard that influenced currency systems across the continent and beyond. Indeed, the word "dollar" evolved from "thaler." The Kutná Hora silver mines, among the most productive in medieval Europe, provided material for the Prague Groschen and later thalers, making Bohemia a center of European minting. Czech mints became renowned for their advanced metallurgical techniques and artistic coin designs, contributing significantly to the economic strength of the Bohemian kingdom and later the Habsburg monarchy.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CZECHIA_MINT_HELP">			
				<Text>Czech replacement for the [ICON_BUILDING_MINT] Mint. Costs 25% less [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production to construct. Provides +2 [ICON_GOLD] Gold from [ICON_RES_IRON] Iron in addition to standard mint resources. Includes 1 [ICON_GREAT_MERCHANT] Great Merchant [ICON_CITIZEN_GOLD] Specialist slot.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CZECHIA_MINT_STRATEGY">			
				<Text>The Thaler Mint is a versatile improvement on the standard Mint, available at the same technology but costing 25% less [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production. Beyond providing the usual bonuses for gold, silver, and copper resources, it also gains bonuses from [ICON_RES_IRON] Iron, making it valuable even in cities without traditional mint resources. The included Merchant specialist slot helps generate additional [ICON_GOLD] Gold and Great Merchant points.</Text>
			</Row>
			
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_CZECHIA_DESC">				
				<Text>Czech Republic</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_CZECHIA_SHORT_DESC">			
				<Text>Czechia</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_CZECHIA_ADJECTIVE">			
				<Text>Czech</Text>
			</Row>
			
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_CZECHIA_LEGION">			
				<Text>Czechoslovak Legion</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_CZECHIA_LEGION_HELP">			
				<Text>Czech replacement for the [ICON_UNIT_FOREIGN_LEGION] Foreign Legion. In addition to the usual abilities of a Foreign Legion, the Czechoslovak Legion does not require a specific [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Policy[ENDCOLOR] to be unlocked, costs 33% less [ICON_GOLD] Gold to purchase, and gains a 33% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat bonus against civilizations with a different [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Ideology[ENDCOLOR].</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_CZECHIA_LEGION_STRATEGY">			
				<Text>The Czechoslovak Legion represents the famous fighting force that distinguished itself during World War I. Unlike the standard Foreign Legion, it doesn't require the Volunteer Army policy to be purchased, and costs 33% less [ICON_GOLD] Gold when bought. It retains the 20% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat bonus when fighting outside friendly territory and gains an additional 33% bonus when fighting civilizations with different ideologies, making it particularly powerful in ideological conflicts during the late game.</Text>
			</Row>
			
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_CZECHIA_DESC">			
				<Text>+100% [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Religious Pressure[ENDCOLOR] towards your own cities. Choose a [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Reformation[ENDCOLOR] belief upon [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Enhancing[ENDCOLOR] a [ICON_RELIGION] Religion (if not picked already).</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_CZECHIA_SHORT_DESC">			
				<Text>Hussite Fervor</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_CZECHIA">			
				<Text>Vladislav II</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_CZECHIA_PEDIA_HEADING_1">			
				<Text>History</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_CZECHIA_PEDIA_TEXT_1">			
				<Text>Vladislav II Jagiellon (1456-1516), King of Bohemia from 1471 and King of Hungary and Croatia from 1490, was a member of the Jagiellon dynasty who ruled during a significant transitional period in Central European history. Known for his mild temperament and diplomatic acumen, Vladislav ascended to the Bohemian throne after the death of the Hussite king George of Poděbrady, and was selected partly because he promised religious tolerance in a kingdom divided between Catholics and Hussites. His reign in Bohemia was characterized by his efforts to balance royal authority with the growing power of the nobility and urban communities. In 1490, he was elected King of Hungary following the death of Matthias Corvinus, creating a personal union between the two kingdoms. Though sometimes criticized for his perceived weakness in standing up to the nobility (earning him the nickname "King Dobře," or "King All-Right," for his tendency to agree with whatever was proposed), Vladislav was in reality a shrewd ruler who preferred negotiation to confrontation. His architectural legacy includes the magnificent Vladislav Hall in Prague Castle, one of the most spectacular late Gothic spaces in Central Europe. During his reign, Prague experienced significant cultural development, with printing presses established and Renaissance influences beginning to appear alongside Gothic traditions. The legal code he established in 1500, known as the Vladislav Land Ordinance, remained a foundation of Czech law for centuries. While not remembered as a military leader or forceful monarch, Vladislav II's diplomatic approach and cultural patronage made him an important figure in Czech history who maintained peace and prosperity during his 45-year reign.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_CZECHIA_PEDIA">			
				<Text>Vladislav II</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_CZECHIA_PEDIA_NAME">			
				<Text>Vladislav II Jagiellon</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_CZECHIA_PEDIA_SUBTITLE">			
				<Text>King of Bohemia and Hungary</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_CZECHIA_PEDIA_LIVED">			
				<Text>1456-1516 AD</Text>
			</Row>
			
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_0">			
				<Text>Prague</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_1">			
				<Text>Brno</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_2">			
				<Text>Ostrava</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_3">			
				<Text>Plzeň</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_4">			
				<Text>Olomouc</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_5">			
				<Text>Liberec</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_6">			
				<Text>České Budějovice</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_7">			
				<Text>Hradec Králové</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_8">			
				<Text>Ústí nad Labem</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_9">			
				<Text>Pardubice</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_10">			
				<Text>Zlín</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_11">			
				<Text>Karlovy Vary</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_12">			
				<Text>Jihlava</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_13">			
				<Text>Kladno</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_14">			
				<Text>Most</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_15">			
				<Text>Opava</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_16">			
				<Text>Frýdek-Místek</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_17">			
				<Text>Děčín</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_18">			
				<Text>Chomutov</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_19">			
				<Text>Přerov</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CZECHIA_20">			
				<Text>Jablonec nad Nisou</Text>
			</Row>
			
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CZECHIA_0">			
				<Text>František</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CZECHIA_1">			
				<Text>Milada</Text>
				<Gender>feminine</Gender>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CZECHIA_2">			
				<Text>Karel</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CZECHIA_3">			
				<Text>Božena</Text>
				<Gender>feminine</Gender>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CZECHIA_4">			
				<Text>Jan</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CZECHIA_5">			
				<Text>Ludmila</Text>
				<Gender>feminine</Gender>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CZECHIA_6">			
				<Text>Václav</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CZECHIA_7">			
				<Text>Josef</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CZECHIA_8">			
				<Text>Zdenka</Text>
				<Gender>feminine</Gender>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CZECHIA_9">			
				<Text>Miloš</Text>
			</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>
