<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>

	<Language_en_US>
		<!-- Mughals -->
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DAWN_OF_MAN_MUGHALS_TEXT">			
				<Text>Blessings upon you, Akbar the Great, wise ruler of the Mughal Empire! Your leadership transformed a realm of disparate peoples into one of history's most powerful and prosperous empires. Your administrative brilliance and religious tolerance fostered an era of unprecedented cultural and artistic achievement. Under your reign, the Mughal Empire expanded across the Indian subcontinent through both conquest and diplomacy. Your Din-i-Ilahi faith and Sulh-i-kul policy of religious harmony helped unite a diverse population, while your patronage of the arts, literature, and architecture left a legacy that still inspires the world today.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]O great emperor, your people call for your wisdom once more. Can you build an empire that honors diverse faiths and cultures? Can you create a civilization that will stand the test of time?
				</Text>
			</Row>
			
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MUGHALS_CARAVANSARY">				
				<Text>Mansabdari Estate</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MUGHALS_CARAVANSARY_PEDIA">			
				<Text>The Mansabdari system was a unique administrative structure established by Emperor Akbar that formed the backbone of the Mughal Empire's civil and military administration. Under this system, imperial officers known as mansabdars were assigned ranks (mansabs) that determined their status, responsibilities, and compensation. Each mansabdar maintained estates that served as centers of local governance and military recruitment. These estates not only strengthened imperial control but also served as cultural centers that promoted Mughal artistic and architectural styles. The system helped integrate diverse ethnic and religious groups into the empire's administrative framework, reflecting the Mughals' skill at incorporating various cultural traditions into their governance model.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MUGHALS_CARAVANSARY_HELP">			
				<Text>Mughal replacement for the [ICON_BUILDING_CARAVANSARY]Caravansary. Available at Currency (vs. Horseback Riding). Provides +10 City [ICON_STRENGTH] Strength, +2 [ICON_GOLD] Gold and +3 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture if the city has a garrison.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MUGHALS_CARAVANSARY_STRATEGY">			
				<Text>The Mansabdari Estate is available at a different technology than the Caravansary it replaces, requiring Currency rather than Horseback Riding. Beyond improving land trade routes, it provides significant defensive bonuses to your cities and additional [ICON_GOLD] Gold and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture when the city is garrisoned, encouraging a balanced approach to growth and defense.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_MUGHALS_DESC">				
				<Text>Mughal Empire</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_MUGHALS_SHORT_DESC">			
				<Text>Mughals</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_MUGHALS_ADJECTIVE">			
				<Text>Mughal</Text>
			</Row>
			
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MUGHALS_CANNON">			
				<Text>Zafarbaksh</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_MUGHALS_CANNON">			
				<Text>The Zafarbaksh, meaning "victory bestower" in Persian, was an advanced artillery piece developed during the Mughal Empire's military prime. Mughal artillery benefited from a combination of Ottoman, Persian, and indigenous Indian engineering traditions, creating weapons that were both mobile and powerful. While European cannons of the period were often unwieldy in the varied terrain of the subcontinent, Mughal engineers modified their designs with lighter materials and improved carriage systems. Under Emperor Akbar's military reforms, these cannons became a cornerstone of Mughal battlefield supremacy, with specialized crews trained to rapidly deploy and reposition them during battles. The Zafarbaksh cannons were particularly feared for their effective range and mobility, allowing Mughal forces to outmaneuver opponents while maintaining superior firepower. The Mughal's mastery of metallurgy also enabled them to cast more uniform and reliable cannon barrels that could withstand repeated firing.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MUGHALS_CANNON_HELP">			
				<Text>Mughal replacement for the [ICON_UNIT_CANNON] Cannon. Has a higher [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength (18 vs 14), higher [ICON_RANGE_STRENGTH] Ranged Strength (23 vs 20), improved [ICON_MOVES] Movement (3 vs 2), and has no sight penalty, but is more costly to build.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MUGHALS_CANNON_STRATEGY">			
				<Text>The Zafarbaksh is a powerful and mobile siege weapon that excels at taking cities. With higher combat and ranged strength than the standard Cannon, plus an extra movement point and no sight penalties, it can position effectively for attacks. While more expensive to produce, its superior mobility and firepower make it a worthy investment for expanding your empire through conquest. Unlike other unique units however, the Zafarbaksh's special abilities do not carry over when it upgrades to Artillery.</Text>
			</Row>
			
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MUGHALS_DESC">			
				<Text>Cities with a dominant [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Foreign[ENDCOLOR] [ICON_RELIGION] Religion yield +1 [ICON_RESEARCH] Science, +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture, and +1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold for every 4 [ICON_CITIZEN] Population in the city. [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Holy[ENDCOLOR] cities of [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Foreign[ENDCOLOR] [ICON_RELIGION] Religions receive the same bonus if at least one of your original cities has been converted to that [ICON_RELIGION] Religion. +2 [ICON_GOLDEN_AGE] Golden Age points from [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]National[ENDCOLOR] and [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]World[ENDCOLOR] Wonders.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MUGHALS_SHORT_DESC">			
				<Text>Diverse Administrators</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MUGHALS">			
				<Text>Akbar</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MUGHALS_PEDIA_HEADING_1">			
				<Text>History</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MUGHALS_PEDIA_TEXT_1">			
				<Text>Jalaluddin Muhammad Akbar (1542-1605), known as Akbar the Great, was the third Mughal emperor who ruled from 1556 to 1605. Ascending the throne at just 13 years of age, Akbar transformed the Mughal Empire from a relatively small kingdom into one of the world's greatest powers. His military campaigns expanded Mughal control across most of the Indian subcontinent, but it was his administrative and cultural innovations that truly defined his reign. Akbar's most significant achievement was developing systems of governance that integrated Hindu and Muslim traditions, creating a stable foundation for a diverse empire. His policy of religious tolerance, embodied in his principle of Sulh-i-kul ("peace with all"), was revolutionary for its time. He abolished the jizya tax on non-Muslims, appointed Hindus to high government positions, and even created a syncretic religious movement called Din-i-Ilahi that borrowed elements from various faiths. Under Akbar's patronage, art, architecture, and literature flourished, creating the distinctive Indo-Islamic culture that characterizes the Mughal legacy. The Mansabdari administrative system he developed remained the backbone of Mughal governance for generations. Akbar's pragmatic policies of religious and cultural accommodation established a model of pluralistic rule that would influence Indian governance for centuries.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MUGHALS_PEDIA">			
				<Text>Akbar</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MUGHALS_PEDIA_NAME">			
				<Text>Akbar the Great</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MUGHALS_PEDIA_SUBTITLE">			
				<Text>Emperor of the Mughal Empire</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MUGHALS_PEDIA_LIVED">			
				<Text>1542-1605 AD</Text>
			</Row>
			
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_0">			
				<Text>Delhi</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_1">			
				<Text>Agra</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_2">			
				<Text>Fatehpur Sikri</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_3">			
				<Text>Lahore</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_4">			
				<Text>Kabul</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_5">			
				<Text>Multan</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_6">			
				<Text>Ahmadabad</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_7">			
				<Text>Patna</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_8">			
				<Text>Srinagar</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_9">			
				<Text>Dacca</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_10">			
				<Text>Thatta</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_11">			
				<Text>Burhanpur</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_12">			
				<Text>Jaunpur</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_13">			
				<Text>Aurangabad</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_14">			
				<Text>Hyderabad</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_15">			
				<Text>Bijapur</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_16">			
				<Text>Ajmer</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_17">			
				<Text>Allahabad</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_18">			
				<Text>Lucknow</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_19">			
				<Text>Panipat</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MUGHALS_20">			
				<Text>Peshawar</Text>
			</Row>
			
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MUGHALS_0">			
				<Text>Birbal</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MUGHALS_1">			
				<Text>Noorjahan</Text>
				<Gender>feminine</Gender>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MUGHALS_2">			
				<Text>Todar Mal</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MUGHALS_3">			
				<Text>Mumtaz</Text>
				<Gender>feminine</Gender>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MUGHALS_4">			
				<Text>Jahangir</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MUGHALS_5">			
				<Text>Roshanara</Text>
				<Gender>feminine</Gender>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MUGHALS_6">			
				<Text>Dara Shikoh</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MUGHALS_7">			
				<Text>Aurangzeb</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MUGHALS_8">			
				<Text>Jahanara</Text>
				<Gender>feminine</Gender>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MUGHALS_9">			
				<Text>Bairam Khan</Text>
			</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>
